Well.
글쎄요
Hi there.
안녕하세요
So you've made it to day two of week eight, and I am super grateful that you've been hanging on, and
8주 차 중 이틀째예요 지금까지 버텨줘서 정말 고마워요 4일
that you're now at the point where there are four more days to go.
더 남은 시점에 도달했다는 것도요
And let me tell you something this day, this is probably the toughest day of the lot of the entire
한마디만 하자면 오늘 코스가 전체 코스 중 가장 힘들 거예요
So if you survive through this day and you're on top of it and you're getting it and you're running
오늘 하루를 무사히 넘기고 모든 걸 파악하고 코드를 실행하고
the code and it's all making sense, then you you're already basically mastering LM engineering.
모든 게 말이 된다면 여러분은 이미 LM 엔지니어링을 통달한 거예요
This is what it's about.
이게 핵심이에요
Today is going to be tough.
오늘은 힘들 거예요
Be prepared.
준비하세요
But as it happens it's going to be really interesting.
하지만 정말 재미있을 거예요
And we're going to get some great achievements done.
Get in get 멋진 성과를 거두게 될 거예요
So four days to go of the eight week journey to LM mastery.
LM 마스터링까지 8주 여정이 4일 남았네요
We're in the home stretch.
이제 거의 다 왔어요
You can already, of course generate text and code with frontier models, with open source, with hugging
물론 이미 오픈 소스 모델로 텍스트와 코드를 생성할 수 있고 얼굴을 앞으로
face back to front, you can follow a strategy to solve problems with curating data sets, which is
당길 수 있으며 기본 모델을 만들기 어려운 큐레이팅 데이터 집합으로 문제를 해결하는
hard making baseline models and fine tuning frontier models, and then carrying out a full end to end
전략을 따를 수 있고 오픈 소스 LMS를 미세 조정하는 풀-엔드 투-엔드
process to fine tune open source LMS.
프로세스를 수행할 수 있죠
And finally, what we did last time is taking our fine tuned LMS and deploying it to production.
마지막으로, 지난번에 한 건 잘 조정된 LMS를 프로덕션에 배포하는 거였죠
We use modal.
우린 모듈을 써요
There are many others, but modal is great, and we use it in such a way that you can just write a simple
다른 것도 많지만 Modal도 훌륭합니다 간단한 파이썬 코드를
piece of Python code that can run locally.
작성해서 로컬에서 실행할 수 있죠
Apparently it looks like it's running locally, but it in fact it is calling out to your model running
로컬에서 실행되는 것처럼 보이지만 사실은 클라우드에서 실행되는 모델에
on the cloud in modal.
호출하는 거예요
Paying only for what you use.
사용료만 지불하는 거죠
So today we take a side step to look at more pricing models as we build our final final pricing model.
오늘은 추가로 가격 모델을 살펴봅니다 최종 가격 모델을 만드는 동안에요
That will be what's called an ensemble, a combination of multiple models.
그게 앙상블이 될 거예요 여러 모델을 합친 거죠
We're going to go back to Rag, and we're going to use Rag to build a frontier model solution that will
다시 Rag로 돌아가 거대한 크롬 데이터 스토어에 대항할 프런티어 모델
operate against a massive Chrome data store.
솔루션을 개발할 거예요
And to make things different to last time, we're not going to use Lang chain.
그리고 전과는 다르게 랑체인을 사용하지 않을 거예요
We're just going to directly look up in the vector store and use that to build our prompt ourselves,
벡터 스토어에서 직접 찾아보고 프롬프트를 구축하는데 사용합니다,
which is good.
좋은 일이죠
Good to understand exactly how it works under the covers.
이불 밑의 일을 정확히 이해하게 돼서 좋네요
We're going to then build this ensemble model with a high level of expertise and be able to deliver
그런 다음 높은 수준의 전문성을 가진 이 앙상블 모델을 만들 겁니다 그리고 생산
production ready code, calling a number of models.
준비 코드를 제공하고 여러 모델을 호출할 수 있죠
And I think perhaps the most important thing to say here is that whilst a lot of what we'll be doing
여기서 가장 중요한 건 우리가 하는 많은 일이 이전에 해 본
is something of a repeat of things we've done before, just in a bit more of an industrial strength
일을 반복하는 것이긴 하지만 좀 더 산업적인 방식으로요
way, this is about solidifying what you've learned.
비트를 더 탄탄하게 만드는 거죠
This is about going from the point of being fairly confident with different aspects of LM engineering
LM 엔지니어링의 다양한 측면에서 상당히 확신하는 지점에서 고급으로
into being advanced, and so do take the time to go through the code and take this as an opportunity
가는 겁니다 그러니 코드를 검토할 시간을 갖고 이걸 기회로 삼아 연습,
to practice, practice, practice, and get to the point of feeling like you've built true expertise.
연습, 연습 진정한 전문 지식을 구축했다는 느낌이 들도록 하세요
All right.
좋아요
So quick, a reminder on what is the project we're working on here.
우리가 작업하는 프로젝트가 뭔지 다시 한 번 보죠
Project called The Price is Right building this autonomous Agentic framework agent workflows that will
가격은 오른쪽 프로젝트라는 자율적 에이전트 프레임워크를 구축하는 겁니다 에이전트
watch for when deals get published online, estimate their prices and send a push notification if it
워크플로는 온라인 거래가 공개될 때를 주시하고 가격을 예측하고 가격에 따라
looks like this is a bargain and we are going to have these different agents collaborating to solve
푸시 알림을 보냅니다 여러 에이전트가 문제를 해결하기 위해 협업할 겁니다
the problem, including our frontier busting model, our fine tuned model that significantly outperformed
그중에는 개척자 단속 모델인 미세 튜닝 모델도 있습니다 GPT 4와 클로드보다 현저히 뛰어나죠
All right, so you may remember last time I showed you this diagram that showed our agent workflows,
지난번에 이 다이어그램을 보여드린 걸 기억하실 겁니다 에이전트 워크플로를 보여드렸죠 왼쪽은 사용자
the user interface on the left, the framework that we'll be using, planning agents to coordinate activities.
인터페이스 우리가 사용할 프레임워크입니다 에이전트가 활동을 조율하도록 계획하는 거죠
And then the three the scanning agent looking for promising deals, ensemble estimating prices and a
그리고 유망한 계약을 찾아주는 스캐닝 요원 세 명 앙상블 가격 산정 푸시
messaging agent that will send us push notifications.
알림을 보내줄 메시지 요원 한 명요
So I wanted to mention that this was a bit of a simplification, because the ensemble agent itself will
이건 약간 단순화됐다는 걸 말씀드리고 싶었어요 앙상블 비트 자체가 세 가지
be calling out to three different models.
모델을 부를 테니까요
It's going to be calling a frontier agent, which is going to be a Rag workflow to price products based
프런티어 에이전트를 호출할 거예요 검색할 수 있는 많은 기존 제품 인벤토리에 기반을
on an inventory of lots of existing products that it can look up.
둔 가격 매기는 래그 워크플로우죠
It's a perfect use case for rag.
걸레로 쓰기 딱 좋아요
Of course, you may have already thought of it as I say, so you may have already been wondering why
물론 제가 말씀드린 대로 이미 생각해 보셨을 테니 왜 이걸 시도도 안 했나 궁금하실
we didn't even try this.
거예요
Well, we're going to.
그렇게 될 거예요
Today, the ensemble agent will use the specialist agent that we already have and built and have like
오늘 앙상블 에이전트는 우리가 이미 만들어둔 특수 에이전트를 사용할 거예요 대표할
a specialist agent class to represent, and it's going to use a random forest agent, which will be
특수 에이전트 클래스 같은 거죠 임의 숲 에이전트를 사용할 건데 전통적인 머신 러닝
an agent using a random forest traditional machine learning approach.
접근법으로 임의 숲 에이전트를 만들 거예요
Except there's going to be a twist.
반전이 있을 거예요
It's going to be using vector embeddings that will use a transformer architecture.
변압기 구조를 사용할 벡터 내장화를 사용할 거예요
So it is a sort of modern take on traditional ML.
전통적인 ML을 현대적으로 재해석한 거군요
So basically today we are going to be working on all of the icons there in red.
기본적으로 오늘은 저기 빨간 아이콘들을 작업할 거예요
We're going to be working on the ensemble agent.
앙상블 에이전트를 만들 거예요
We've already built the specialist agent.
특수 요원은 이미 만들었어요
So the other two will be part of our conquest today.
나머지 둘은 오늘 정복에 참여할 거예요
And we will end today with an ensemble agent that is able to calculate prices, drawing on multiple
그리고 오늘 마무리로 앙상블 에이전트가 가격을 계산하고 다른 평가자 여럿을
other estimators.
끌어들일 거예요
That's the challenge.
그게 도전 과제죠
Let's get over to JupyterLab.
Get it JupyterLab으로 가죠